NIC ROBERTS NICROBERTS.CO.UK

LONDON BASED LEAD PRODUCT DESIGNER & ART DIRECTOR.

I have over 10 years of experience creating branding and digital products for lifestyle and retail brands.

Having worked both in-house and agency side for a number of successful brands, I have gained real insight and knowledge into what makes a great product. I am skilled in designing effective solutions, with an emphasis on user and business needs, that are simple and beautifully designed.

Experience

Jan 2021 - Present

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER MATTER OF FORM

Lead branding and full website design projects for a number of brands in the luxury hospitality and retail sectors. Clients include Sani Resorts, D Maris Bay & Belmond.

Lead pitches and presentations with external clients including workshops and design reviews.

Art directed shoots abroad with a large production teams including models, stylists, producers and photographers.

April 2020 - Jan 2021

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER FREELANCE

Designed digital experiences for different product launches for a wide range of brands. Involved in all aspects of the delivery from UX,UI,Interaction design and strategy.

Projects include a complete app redesign for an online retailer based in the UAE; homepage redesigns and UX improvements for the worlds first carbon-negative knitwear brand; and Product and Artist page designs for a luxury online Art retailer.

Aug 2019 - April 2020

DIGITAL DESIGN MANAGER SELFRIDGES

Supporting the Head of Digital Design, guiding a team of designers to produce highly executed outputs across the website from editorial design and UI to motion graphics.

Design engaging and inspiring editorial content and creative campaigns, bringing ideas to the table and recognising new opportunities of how these can be imagined within our digital channels.

Work hand-in-hand with UX and Development, supporting with wider site design and improvements; constantly looking to push forward the Selfridges digital experience.

Aug 2018 - Aug 2019

DIGITAL DESIGN TEAM LEAD HARRODS

Lead a design team of UI, UX, Campaign, Marketing and Email Designers, ensuring consistency and quality across all channels.

Drove project ideation and conceptual development of creative and design direction.

Lead design projects, working closely with the UX team to create design solutions that were entirely user focused, keeping in mind accessibility guidelines and SEO.

NIC ROBERTS NICROBERTS.CO.UK

April 2016 - Aug 2018

LEAD DIGITAL DESIGNER TOPSHOPTOPMAN

Lead a design team of designers, introducing solid design principles and ensuring consistency and smooth execution of all online creative.

Reviewed design work from designers and provided effective direction and feedback, managed team resources, implemented process work-flow and project timings.

Lead large design projects, including a site re-platform, to improve user experience and drive sales.

April 2015 - April 2016

DIGITAL DESIGNER ASOS

Worked across the Creative Technology and Commercial departments to create campaigns and branded content and to improve innovation across the site.

Created concepts, designs and pitches for brand partnerships and collaborations, ensuring a focus on innovation and interactivity.

Art directed both model and still life shoots, adhering to ASOS brand identity.

Sept 2013 - April 2015

MULTI-CHANNEL DESIGNER WAREHOUSE

Designed and built weekly emails, homepages and content pages for the website using HTML/CSS. Created digital campaigns and features from initial concepts through to design and implementation.

Lead designer for responsive website redesign project in August 2014 including homepage, product and category pages. Worked alongside developers to improve website design, functionality and overall user experience.

Education

2008 - 2011

BA (HONS) FASHION PROMOTION & COMMUNICATION - 2:1 SOUTHAMPTON SOLENT UNIVERSITY

Centred around how fashion is communicated and promoted creatively through different media. Covering a wide range of disciplines such as digital and print graphic design, Illustration, photography, art direction, styling, trend forecasting, PR, buying & merchandising and visual merchandising.

Skills

Disciplines UI / UX / PRODUCT DESIGN / DIGITAL MARKETING DESIGN / PROTOTYPING /

BRANDING / TYPOGRAPHY / ART DIRECTION / HTML & CSS / VIDEO EDITING /

ANIMATION / ICONOGRAPHY / PRINT DESIGN / PACKAGING DESIGN

Programmes FIGMA / SKETCH / PHOTOSHOP / ILLUSTRATOR / INDESIGN / XD / AFTER EFFECTS